Drishya Dinesh T P

https://github.com/drishya-dinesh https://drishya-dinesh.github.io/

Summary

Dynamic and motivated software Developer with a strong dedication to providing top-tier solutions, remaining updated with industry advancements and optimal methodologies. Committed to enhancing company achievements through python programming skills, data analysis expertise and knowledge of software development best practices to contribute to a diligent team and drive project success.

Professional Experience

Technical Support Representative, Voysus CE Inc. -Toronto, Canada

Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

• Resolved hardware based issues ensuring a satisfactory resolution for the customer while adhering to company policies and procedures.

Student Intern, Cambrian College -Ontario, Canada

Oct 2021 - Jun 2022

- Facilitated real-time projects under the surveillance of superiors by delivering documentations and presentations.
- Researched industry best practices and synthesized findings into actionable recommendations for the product development.

Software Developer Intern, Knowledge Lens -Bengaluru, India

Aug 2018 – Sep 2019

- Conducted surveys to elevate performance from clients and resolved bugs and complex issues to maintain high quality deliverables.
- Merged with Multi-National Companies with projects, implemented Responsive and mobile first strategies in each projects.

Projects

E-commerce Marketplace, (capstone project)

Responsive web application platform for both users and sellers to market products featuring Real-Time chat room, Product Display and Collections.

• Technology used: Authentication and validation · Firebase · Bootstrap · Angular

Digital Gallery blog 🛮

Collection of self photographed portraits developed using html5 and css. Deployed public using git and hosted using netify account.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap.

User authentication single page application built with attractive interface backed up by database validation using flask framework.

• Technologies used: Angular, Python, PostgreSQL.

Weather predication Application 🛭

Integrated open API to display current weather with related location wise information.

Technologies used: HTML,CSS, OpenAPI

Skills

- · Consistency and critical thinking
- Interpersonal skills and time management ability
- Web development using Flask, HTML/CSS/JavaScript/ReactJS
- API integration using REST API and third party APIs.
- Adaptability and problem solving skills
- Version control system using git and gitHub

Education

Mobile Application Development, Cambrian College, Ontario, Canada

Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

Bachelor's in Computer Science, Kannur University, Kerala, India

Jul 2015 - Jul 2018

Certificates

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

• Google IT Automation with python professional certificate